delta.edu 2019-08-14

# Privacy Statement - Delta College

This online privacy statement is intended to inform you of the ways in which this website (“Site”) collects information, the uses to which that information will be put, and the ways in which we protect information you choose to provide us. 

Use of this Site is subject to all applicable state and federal laws, as well as general Delta College policies. 

**Information Collected**

This Site collects two general types of information: (a) information you voluntarily provide to us, which may include personal information (such as your name, address, email address, etc.), and (b) information we collect automatically when you visit this Site through cookies, third-party tracking technologies and server logs. 

**Information Voluntarily Provided by You**

This Site will only collect personal information that you knowingly and voluntarily provide, for example, by responding to surveys, completing membership forms, sending emails, etc. It is this Site’s general practice to use personal information only for the purposes for which it was requested and any additional uses specifically stated on the Site. However, information collected through this Site may be subject to Delta College’s obligation to respond to subpoenas, court orders, discovery requests, and requests for public records under the Michigan Freedom of Information Act. Further, the disclosure of information collected through this Site is subject to the provisions of the Family Educational Rights & Privacy Act. 

We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit or provide, and you do so at your own risk. Although this Site has security measures in place to protect personal information provided to us by users, users should also take steps to protect personal information. One way to do this is to close all web browsers after using the Site. Information disclosed in chat rooms, news groups, forums, message boards and similar contexts may become public. Users should therefore exercise caution before disclosing personal information in such contexts. 

**Information Collection**

This Site collects information automatically through the use of cookies, third-party tracking technologies and server logs. This information does not include any personal information. We use this information primarily to monitor the use of this Site and to make improvements. We may share this data with partners in order to enhance the functionality of this Site. 

**Cookies**

“Cookies” are small text files used to collect information about website activity. No personal information is collected through our use of cookies. This Site uses cookies to identify you on this Site on return visits. This Site also uses Cookies (via Google) to become aware when you visited the Delta College website, so you can be reached with Delta College-related advertising on other websites across the Internet (a process called “remarketing”). 

You have the option of disabling or not accepting cookies by changing the preferences on your browser. If you opt to disable cookies, you will still be able to use certain sections of our Site. However, you will not be able to use any parts of this Site that require a login (e.g., accessing secured content, posting to message boards, etc). 

**Third-Party Tracking Technology**

This Site uses a tracking technology called Google Analytics to obtain Site usage information such as users’ Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, Internet domain and host names, browser software, and the date and time that the Site is visited. Data obtained through Google Analytics does not include and is not linked to any personal information. Data from Google Analytics allows us to monitor the use of this Site, understand how users find our Site, and improve the Site’s function and content. 

Site usage data collected through Google Analytics is not shared with other Google products and tools. Our use of Google Analytics is in compliance with Google’s Terms of Service and Delta College’s own guidelines. Google provides more information about Google’s privacy practices and information on how to opt out of Google Analytics tracking of your web browsing at <https://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/learn/privacy.html>. 

This Site uses Google custom search, which allows us to feature specialized information in web searches and create a customized search engine based on Google Search. 

**Server Logs**

Our web servers routinely generate logs that contain the following types of information each time the Site is used: 

  * The date, time and length of your visit.
  * The path taken through our Site and the browser being used.
  * The list of files downloaded and the amount of time spent viewing video or audio files.
  * The IP Address of the computer accessing our Site.
  * Any errors encountered.

This information is used primarily to monitor the functioning and integrity of the Site and other Delta College websites. 

**Links**

This Site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we do not control or claim any responsibility for the privacy practices or content of other sites. We encourage users to read the privacy statements of each website they visit. 

**Choice/Opt-out**

Our users are given the opportunity to receive or not receive communications from Delta College. However, at this time this Site does not manage or send communications. 

**Changes to Privacy Statement**

We reserve the right to alter or amend this privacy statement at any time and without prior notice. If we make changes to our privacy statement, we will indicate this on our home page. 

**Disclaimer**

Neither Delta College, nor any of its units, programs, employees, agents or individual trustees, shall be liable for any improper or incorrect use of information obtained through the use of this Site. 

**Consent**

By using this Site you consent to the terms of this privacy statement.

**Questions and Feedback**

Your questions, comments and concerns are always welcome. Please send us your feedback regarding the privacy statement or any other issues at [info@delta.edu](mailto:info@delta.edu).
